Guide to the Kenneth Walter Cameron Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Kenneth Walter Cameron papers
1727-1987
MS 124
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
82.75
The papers consist of autographs and collected letters, sermons, teaching materials, research notes and documents, and the typescript of Kenneth Cameron's master's thesis on Othello (1931). A large part of the papers relates to the Church of the Holy Trinity in Hartford, Connecticut and contains a substantial collection of the sermons, writings and speeches of the Reverend Ernest Fremery Miel, manuscripts of Sir Arthur Gorges, sermons of Joseph G. H. Barry and papers relating to the construction of the church, 1870-1874. Also in the papers are a number of Civil War documents, including papers of P. P. Pitkin and letters to the U. S. Treasury from officers of the U. S. Colored Regiments. Another group of letters, written between 1885 and 1917, to Samuel Hart, concerns the American Book of Common Prayer. Also included are research materials on the Concord School of Philosophy and Literature.
Cameron, Kenneth Walter, 1908-2006
Conditions Governing Access
The sealed containers of Cameron letters and miscellany are unprocessed and may contain sensitive information or be in a physical state that would prohibit use. Researchers wishing to request access should email mssa.assist@yale.edu requesting specific box numbers in order to initiate the review process, which may take several weeks.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Kenneth W. Cameron, 1936, 1960 onward; gift of the University of Connecticut, 2000.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of autographs and collected letters, sermons, teaching materials, research notes and documents, and the typescript of Kenneth Cameron's master's thesis on Othello (1931). A large part of the papers relates to the Church of the Holy Trinity in Hartford, Connecticut and contains a substantial collection of the sermons, writings and speeches of the Reverend Ernest Fremery Miel, manuscripts of Sir Arthur Gorges, sermons of Joseph G. H. Barry and papers relating to the construction of the church, 1870-1874. Also in the papers are a number of Civil War documents, including papers of P. P. Pitkin and letters to the U. S. Treasury from officers of the U. S. Colored Regiments. Another group of letters, written between 1885 and 1917, to Samuel Hart, concerns the American Book of Common Prayer. Also included are research materials on the Concord School of Philosophy and Literature.
Biographical / Historical
Kenneth Walter Cameron was born on October 12, 1908, in Martins Ferry, Ohio. He received a B.A. degree (1930) and a M.A. degree (1931) from West Virginia University, a S.T.B. from General Theological Seminary (1935), and a Ph.D. from Yale (1940). Cameron was ordained an Episcopal priest in 1935. He taught English at the University of North Carolina (1938-1943), Temple University (1945-1946), and Trinity College (1946-until retirement). Cameron also served as the archivist and historiographer for the Diocese of Connecticut.
African American soldiers; Drawing -- 19th century; Hartford (Conn.) -- Religion; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Participation, African American; Connecticut; Europe; Autographs; Sermons; Clergy; Hart, Samuel, 1845-1917; Barry, Joseph Gayle Hurd, 1858-1931; Godbey, Allen Howard, 1864-1948; Gorges, Arthur, Sir, 1557?-1625; Matthews, Jane M. Cheshire; Miel, Ernest Fremery, 1868-1925; Pitkin, Perley Peabody, 1826-1891; Ward, Leslie, Sir, 1851-1922; Weed, Thurlow, 1797-1882; Cameron, Kenneth Walter, 1908-2006; Church of the Holy Trinity (Hartford, Conn.); Episcopal Church
- Inventory
  - Miel, Rev- Ernest de Fremery, 1868-1925
    - Sermons and papers found in the Trinity Church Paris House, Hartford, with other papers (Box 1–9)
    - Essays, typed
      - "Organization within the Church" (Box 10)
      - "Responsibilities of the Church in the public house problem" (Box 10)
      - "The social life of Israel in the period of monarchy" (Box 10)
    - Speech: "The National Guard and the value of military service" (Box 10)
      General
      For additional Miel papers, See also: box 17
  - Middletown, Conn. Church of the Holy Trinity
    - Papers of the Church of the Holy Trinity, Middletown, Conn. Relate to the construction of the church, 1870-1874; include correspondence, contracts, estimates, invoices, receipts, legal papers, etc. The following correspondents are represented: George D. Hooper, Dr. Joseph w. Alsop, Robert G. Pike, Henry Dudley, A. Putnam and others. (Box 12–13)
  - Barry, Joseph Gayle Hurd, 1858-1931
    - Five looseleaf notebooks of typewritten sermons, 1914, 1915, 1922, 1925 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence, filed chronologically.
    - Barlas, Robert to Geo.Makgill (1), 1835 (Box 11)
    - Bell, Bernard Tiddings, to John R. Diehl (1), 1937 (Box 11)
    - Borah, William E. to Frederick B. Stevenson (1), 1918 (Box 11)
    - Brennan, George to unnamed (1), 1861 (Box 11)
    - Brent, Chas. Henry, to E. deF. Miel (1), 1918 (Box 11)
    - Brenton, Cranston, to E. deF. Miel (1), 1914 (Box 11)
    - Brewster, Benj Harris, Autograph (Box 11)
    - Campbell, Anthony F, Petition with others to Coll.port of N.Y. for Marquis D. Moore (1), 1866 (Box 11)
    - Carter, John F., to E. deF. Miel (1), 1902 (Box 11)
    - Colladay, Samuel Rakestraw, to W.P. Ladd (1), 1927 (Box 11)
    - Crocker, Wm. Tufts, to E. deF. Miel (1), 1914 (Box 11)
    - Curtis, Charles to "My dear Rosenmosser" (1), 1928 (Box 11)
    - Dagwell, Benj.Dunlap, to Sam Holbrook (1), 1938 (Box 11)
    - Davis, John William, to Howard C. Robbins (1), 1922 (Box 11)
    - Devonshire, Spencer Compton Cavendish, 8th duke of, to "Sir" (1), 1890 (Box 11)
    - Dix, John Adams, Pass to himself (1), 1862 (Box 11)
    - Drury, Samuel Smith, to Harold Belshaw (1), 1938 (Box 11)
    - Durant, Frederick C. to E. deF. Miel (1), 1914 (Box 11)
    - Fiske, Geo.McClellan, to William D. Ely (2), 1900,1902 (Box 11)
    - Fosbroke, Hughell Edgar Woodhall, to William P*Ladd (1), 1930 (Box 11)
    - Francis, Joseph Marshall, to Gordon L. Reagan (1), 1937 (Box 11)
    - Gales, Joseph, Bill to William Duffy (1), 1808 (Box 11)
    - Gammack, James to Samuel Hart (1), 1915 (Box 11)
    - Gates, Milo Hudson to W.P. Ladd (1), 1931 (Box 11)
    - Gilbert, George Blodgett, Sr. Autograph on card (1), 1940 (Box 11)
    - Glenn, Charles Leslie, to W.P. Ladd (2), 1931 (Box 11)
    - Glover, Herbert Justison, to W. P. Ladd (1), 1927 (Box 11)
    - Graham, Dwight Worden, to "My dear Cleveland (incomplete) stapled to ALS to E. deF.Miel (2), 1914 (Box 11)
    - Grubb, George, to Samuel Hart (1), 1912 (Box 11)
    - Haslam, Charles R, to Archie H. Burdick (1), 1938 (Box 11)
    - Hay, John, to E. deF. Miel (1), 1901 (Box 11)
    - Hibbard, Angus Smith, to E. deF. Miel (1), 1914 (Box 11)
    - Hobson, Henry Wise, to Alice Graham(Sumner) Camp (1), 1919 (Box 11)
    - Hutchinson, Samuel, Deed (1), 1839 (Box 11)
    - Ireland, Alleyne, Autograph (1), Undated (Box 11)
    - Johnson, Edith A., to Archie H. Burdick, 1938, 1939 (Box 11)
    - Johnston, Alexander, to R.E. Thompson (1), 1882 (Box 11)
    - Kellogg, Charles Poole, Kemp, Richard, to Edward M. Parker (1), 1918 (Box 11)
    - Kidwell, Zedekiah, to J.F. Updegraff (1), 1857 (Box 11)
    - Kennedy, A.R., draft of a letter of resignation (1), 1866 (Box 11)
    - Kisman, Thomas to Wollaston Pym (1), 1832 (Box 11)
    - Kopplemann, Herman Paul, to Paolo Vasquez (2), 1935 (Box 11)
    - Lawrence, John Watson, Petition to Herman J. Redfield for his brother, Effingham W. Lawrence (1), 1853 (Box 11)
    - Leggat, Janie E. to Mr. Townsend (1), 1878 (Box 11)
    - Leonard, Moses Gage, Petition to Coll. of Port of NY for Ezekial W. Houseman (1), 1853 (Box 11)
    - Lewis, John Neher, to E. deF. Miel (3), 1902-1923, 1908 (Box 11)
    - Linsley, John Chauncey, Baptismal certificate of Adele Therese Weave (1), 1899 (Box 11)
    - McAlister, Hill, Signature on letter fromMr. Cameron (1), 1934 (Box 11)
    - McClure, David, Receipt for six pounds to Francis Brown on account of Zachariah Seymour (1), 1798 (Box 11)
    - McCook, Edward Moody, to "My dear sir" (1), undated (Box 11)
    - McIlvaine, Charles Petit, Copy of reply to letter from Alex. Varian (1), 1847 (Box 11)
    - Manning, William Thomas, to Elizabeth McCracken (3), 1937 (Box 11)
    - March, Charles [Wainright] Lease to Conrelius P. VanNess (1), 1844 (Box 11)
    - Cuyler Reynolds (1), 1902 (Box 11)
    - Marvin, Loren Pinckeney Waldo, to E. deF. Miel (1), 1908 (Box 11)
    - Mather, Frederic Gregory, to George Brooks (1), 1883 (Box 11)
    - Mercantile Library Ass'n. Certificate acknolwedging donation of Austin Abbot signd by Lincoln A. Stuart (1), 1895 (Box 11)
    - Merrill, Len I, to E. deF. Miel (1), [1923]? (Box 11)
    - Michie, George R B, to W.P. Ladd (1), 1931 (Box 11)
    - Miel, Ernest deFremery, Carbon copy of letter to children of his parish (1), 1923 (Box 11)
    - Mifflin, George Harrison, to F.J. Garrison (1), 1886 (Box 11)
    - Miller, Harriet Mann, Autograph on last page of letter (1), Undated (Box 11)
    - Minturn, Robert Bowne, to Tholmas Wolcott (1), 1857 (Box 11)
    - Moody, Dwight Lyman, to James W. Eldridge (last page) (1), Undated (Box 11)
    - Morse, Nathan B. Petition to Coll. of Port of NY for William Mullen (1), 1853 (Box 11)
    - M[oulton, Ellen] L[ouise] C[handler], to "My dear" (1), Undated (Box 11)
    - Murphy, Henry Cruse, to Mssrs. Blai and Reeves (1), 1848 (Box 11)
    - Noyes, William Curtis, to S.B. Ruggles (1), Undated (Box 11)
    - Orser, John Petition to Coll.of Port of NY for Ebenezer Hyer (1), 1853 (Box 11)
    - Palmer, George Herbert, to "Dear Sir" (1), 1918 (Box 11)
    - New York Mercantile Library Assn. Certificate to Austin Abbot (1), 1895 (Box 11)
    - Parker, C.H.C., Voucher for pay as clerk to S.C.Harbert, Paymaster (1), 1864 (Box 11)
    - Parrish, Helen L. to E. deF. Mill (1), 1908 (Box 11)
    - Parton, James to R. Westcott (1), 1902 (Box 11)
    - Peck, Annie Smith, to Dr. González-Prada (1), undated (Box 11)
    - Pennsylvania, Infantry 58th Regiment, Discharge of William A. Moore signed by Wlater S. Poor (1), 1864 (Box 11)
    - Penrith, Esme William Howard, 1st baron, Autograph (1), 1928 (Box 11)
    - Perry, James DeWolf, to Archie H. Burdick (2), 1938, 1939 (Box 11)
    - Phelps, Royal to B.K.Phelps (1), 1878 (Box 11)
    - Poore, Benjamin Perley, to "My dear sir" (1), 1885 (Box 11)
    - Porter, Horace, to "Dear Badeau" (1), 1869 (Box 11)
    - Porter, Noah, to S. Irenaus Prime (1), 1881 (Box 11)
    - Pratt, Zadock, Petition for the stepson of John C. Johnson to Coll of Port of NY (1), 1853 (Box 11)
    - Prime, Samuel Lrenaus, to "Mr. Powell" (1), 1874 (Box 11)
    - Proctor, Mary to "Mr.Tracy" Quincy, Josiah, to the Veterans of the Boston Light Infantry (1), 1880 (Box 11)
    - Rees, Sarah, to E. deF. Miel (1), 1913 (Box 11)
    - Rhinelander, Phillip Mercer, to E.deF.Miel (1), 1915 (Box 11)
    - Rideing, William Henry, to W.R. Benjamin (1), 1908 (Box 11)
    - Roberts, Marshall Owen, to James Grant Wilson (1), 1870 (Box 11)
    - Robert, Marshall Owen, Bond to Hugh Maxwell, Coll.of Port of NY (1), 1859 (Box 11)
    - Root, Elihu, to William R. Strickland, Jr. (1), 1925 (Box 11)
    - Rowland, Kate Mason to Walter R. Benjamin (1), Undated (Box 11)
    - Runk, Lewis Barcroft, to W.P. Ladd (3), 1927, 1931 (Box 11)
    - Sanford, Edward, to J.B. Harrison (1), 1852 (Box 11)
    - Sargent, Mary Elizabeth (Fiske) to "Miss Booth" (1), Undated (Box 11)
    - Satterlee, Henry Yaes, to E. deF. Miel (1), 1903 (Box 11)
    - Savage, Minot Judson, to "Dear Sir" (1), 1890 (Box 11)
    - Schell, Augustus, to "Dear Sir" (1), 1879 (Box 11)
    - Schieren, Charles Adolph, To Alfred Chasseaud (1), 1899 (Box 11)
    - Schiff, Jacob Henry to Hamilton Holt (1), 1910 (Box 11)
    - Schofield, John McAllister to William L. Haskin (1), 1892 (Box 11)
    - Scott, Francis Marcoe, to Chester S. Lord (1), 1897 (Box 11)
    - Seccombe, Thomas, to Ernest A. Baker (1), 1910 (Box 11)
    - Shafer, I., to John D. Townsend (1), 1885 (Box 11)
    - Sharp, Joseph W. to E. deF. Miel (1), 1902 (Box 11)
    - Shedd, William Greenough Thayer, to Courtland Palmer (1), 1885 (Box 11)
    - Sheldon, Charles Monroe to Margaret Lee (1), 1899 (Box 11)
    - Shepard, Elliot Fitch, to "Madame Viele" (1), 1866 (Box 11)
    - Sherman, John to "Dear sir" (1), Undated (Box 11)
    - Shoemaker, Henry Wharton, to Wlater R. Benjamin (1), 1925 (Box 11)
    - Skiddy, Francis to Thomas Brown (1), 1866 (Box 11)
    - Sleicher, John Albert, to B.B. Valentine (1), 1900 (Box 11)
    - Sloan, Samuel to "Mr. Butler" (1), 1878 (Box 11)
    - Smith, Goldwin to Susan Dallas (1), Undated (Box 11)
    - Smith, James D. to Charles R. Deacon (1), 1887 (Box 11)
    - Smith, Wesley, Petition to Coll. of Port of NY for Jacob Straus (1), [1853?] (Box 11)
    - Smythe, Henry A. to "My dear Sir" (1), 1866 (Box 11)
    - Somerby, Gustavus A. to George S. Boutwell with latter's reply on letter (1), 1865 (Box 11)
    - Sparks, Thomas Ayres, to W.P. Ladd (1), 1937 (Box 11)
    - Stabler, Walter Brooke to W.P. Ladd (1), 1931 (Box 11)
    - Stanton, Nehemiah P. to E.A. Buck (1), 1882 (Box 11)
    - Starin, John Henry to W.L. Stone (2), 1884, 1886 (Box 11)
    - Stetson, Caleb Rochford to W.L. Ladd (3), 1927-1930 (Box 11)
    - Stetson, Charles Augustus to "dear Gen'l" (1), 1863 (Box 11)
    - Stetson, Francis Lynde, to Mssrs. Townsend & Weed (1), 1881 (Box 11)
    - Stillwell, Silas Moore, to "Dear Phillips" (1), Undated (Box 11)
    - Stoddard, Francis Hovey, to William Abbot (1), Undated (Box 11)
    - Storrs, Henry Randolph Statement concerning a meeting of the committee on manufactures (1), Undated (Box 11)
    - Stranahan, James Samuel Thomas to Jesse C.Green (1), 1888 (Box 11)
    - Stranahan, James Samuel Thomas, Petition to Postmaster of N.Y. for P.G. Lunny 1 (1), Undated (Box 11)
    - Stuart, Robert, to Dr. Shiper (Facsimile) (1), 1940 (Box 11)
    - Sullivan, Algernon Sydney to W.L. Stone (1), 1886 (Box 11)
    - Sullivan, Algernon Sydney to John D. Townsend (1), 1886 (Box 11)
    - Swackhamer, Conrad, Petition to Coll. of Port of NY for Michael Moran (1), 1853 (Box 11)
    - Sweeney, Peter Barr, to C. Monell (1), 1869 (Box 11)
    - S[underline]?Theodore, Receipt to G.T. Strong (1), 1853 (Box 11)
    - S.,W., to "Dear Charles" (1), Undated (Box 11)
    - Taft, Henry Waters, to "Dear Mr. Smith" (1), 1887 (Box 11)
    - Tallmadge, Frederick Augustus to George E. Badger (1), 1841 Tyalor, Moses, Petition to Coll.of Port of NY for George Conklin (Box 11)
    - Taylor, Moses & Co. to Charles T. Mortham & Co. (1), 1851 (Box 11)
    - Thayer, John Milton, to B. Perry (1), 1880 (Box 11)
    - Thorne, Samuel to W.P. Ladd (2), 1930,1931 (Box 11)
    - Tibbits, John Knox, to E.M. Parker (2), 1917, 1918 (Box 11)
    - Travers, William R.Petition for ZMr.Meeker for a position in the Customs House (1), 1866 (Box 11)
    - Tyng, Stephen Higginson, to [My dear sir" (1), 1871 (Box 11)
    - U.S. Army. Ordnance Corps. ALS from W.F.Brinck to Lieut.Col. MacPherson (1), 1862 (Box 11)
    - U S. Custom House, N.Y. Certification to duties paid by L.W. Morris (1), 1868 (Box 11)
    - U.S. Quartermasters dept. receipt to J.V.D. Reeve signed by M.L Ludington (1), 1871 (Box 11)
    - U. S. Consulate. Liverpool, list of invoices signed byL.Fairchild (1), 1877 (Box 11)
    - D. Wright to F.N. Barrett (1), 1891 (Box 11)
    - U.S. Government printing office, Order for a speech of Joseph H. Rainey to be printed (1), undated (Box 11)
    - U.S.Pension Bureau, ALS from J.L.Edwards to J.B. Harrison (1), 1849 (Box 11)
    - U.S. Congress.Senate, Resolution on instructions to committee on printing attested by John W. Forney (1), 1864 (Box 11)
    - U.S. Treasury Dept., Authorization by George Harrington for entry of merchandise by Thomas Dunham (1), 1863 (Box 11)
    - U.S. Treasury dept, LS from Daniel Graham to C.W. Lawrence (1), 1847 (Box 11)
    - U.S. Treasury dept.,LS from Peter Hagner? to Henry Dumas (1), 1818 (Box 11)
    - U.S. Treasury dept. LS from Levi Woodbury to J. Delafield (1), 1835 (Box 11)
    - U.S. Treasury dept.,LS from M.C.Young to Collector of customs at New York (1), 1846 (Box 11)
    - Virginia Central agricultural society, membership certificate to J.H. Frazee signed by James Lyons (1), 1858 (Box 11)
    - Waddington, Samuel to Ernest A. Baker (1), 1907 (Box 11)
    - Walker, M. Penderll to E. deF. Mill (2), 1902 (Box 11)
      Scope and Contents
      1 to brother, Andrew Scott Walker.
    - Ward, Leslie, two cartoons signed by "Spy" (his pseudonym) (1), Undated (Box 11)
    - Watson, John Henry to [Charles) Babcock (1), one on each side of paper, 1884 (Box 11)
    - Watts, Henry M.to Edward Curtis (1), 1844 (Box 11)
    - Weedon Thurlow to"Mrs. Ford" (1), 1864 (Box 11)
    - Wheeler, Ezra, petition to Coll.of Port of NY for James M.B.Child (1), 1866? (Box 11)
    - Willcox, James K. Hamilton, to Thomas Collier Platt with note by latter at bottom (1), 1896 (Box 11)
    - Willet, James C., petition to Coll of Port of NY for John Ludlow (1), Undated (Box 11)
    - Williams, Allen Hamilton to E. deF. Miel (1), 1913 (Box 11)
    - Wilson, Henry to unnamed person (1), Undated (Box 11)
    - Woodford, Stewart Z Lyndon to Horatio C. King (1), Undated (Box 11)
    - Unidentified, to E. deF. Miel (1), 1913 (Box 11)
    - Material on the American Book of Common Prayer, consisting mainly of letters to Dr. Samuel Hart. Persons represented with number and date of letters. (Box 11)
      - Burbidge, Edward, 1939-1903 (2), 1890, 1891 (Box 11)
      - Denslow, Herbert McKenzie (1), 1910 (Box 11)
      - Dowden, John pp. od Edinburgh (4), 1885-1888 (Box 11)
      - Geer, Curtis Manning, 1864- {to Berkeley Divinity School on Dr. Hart's death] (1), 1917 (Box 11)
      - Hall, Arthur Crawshay Alliston (1), 1910 (Box 11)
      - Johnson, George Barent (2), 1910 (Box 11)
      - MacMillan, George Augustin (1), 1891 (Box 11)
      - Grub, The very Rev. George (1), 1912 (Box 11)
      - Mann, Alexander, 1860- (1), 1910 (Box 11)
      - Metcalf, Henry Aikin (2), 1910 (Box 11)
      - Muss-Arnolt, William (5), 1915 (Box 11)
      - Pember, Gilbert Edward (1), 1911 (Box 11)
      - Perry, William Stevens (1), 1891 (Box 11)
      - proctor, Francis, 1812-1905 (9), 1889-1893 (Box 11)
      - Reddish, Bruce V. (2), 1912 (Box 11)
  - Bristol, Rev. Cornelius Gardiner, 1863-1901 (Box 16)
    "Royal Arch Masonry"; Address. "Masonry and the Church" delivered at Hartford, May 10, 1898; and Memorial Day address, Milford, 1897; Harford, 1898
  - Gorges, Sir Arthur, -1625 (Box 16)
    4 envelopes of mss. etc. relating to Sir Arthur Gorges. Includes the following:
    Hartford, Conn. Trinity Church. Miscellaneous papers found in the Parish House with papers of E. deF. Miel.
    Announcement of the coming of the Rev. Raymond Cunningham as Associate to the Rector, Trinity Episcopal Church. List of gifts and memorials and names of contributors, 1905.
    List of gifts and memorials, typed and proofread.
    List of names and addresses of people to whom "List of gifts and memorials" were sent
    Outline of program for teaching 1st, 2nd 3rd grades
    Plea for Easter offerings.
    "Santa Claus"—a play
    Subscription books new organ
    Miscellaneous material: clippings
    Commentary on the T.M.C.A. and other philanthropic activities
  - Johnson, Rev. Edwin Emerson, -1883 (Box 17)
    General note
    "The Church in its relation to the living Christ."
  - Matthews, Jane M. Cheshire, 1838-1842 (Box 17)
    Drawing book and autograph album with drawings laid in or sketched in.
  - Nelson, The Rev. Mr. (Box 17)
    Two sermons sewed together preached in Houghton, Whitb, Weremouth, etc. England, 1727 1743/44
  - Perkins, Haven P (Box 17)
    Ethics, I. Typewritten transcripts of lectures by H.P. Perkins, ca. 1932-1933
  - Pitkin, Col. Perley Peabody, 1826-1891 (Box 17)
    16 documents of the Civil War period to P.P. Pitkin of the Assistant Quartermaster's Office. 10 requisitions for stores, 1863-1864, drawn ON Col. Pitkin and receipted by various officers at Brandy Station, Warrenton Junction, and other points in Virginia; 2 letters to Col. Pitkin, 1863-1864, from officers in the Asst. Quartermaster's Department; 4 U.S. military telegrams to Col. Pitkin, Oct, 1863 from various officers at Headquarters, Army of the Potomac.
  - Protestant Episcopal Church. Commission on preaching mission. (Box 17)
  - Report. The Rt. Rev. David H. Greer, bp., 1844-1919 (Box 17)
  - Tracy, Ruth N (Box 17)
    "Robert Browning", typed essay, Aug 13, 1941. Probably a student of Mr. Cameron in North Carolina.
    Letters to U.S. Treasury from officers of U.S. Colored Regts.
    1865 Jul 3; Aug 4, 7; 15; Oct 3, 6, 11
    1866 Jan 5; Apr 1; Jul 10
  - Genealogical data on various families: (Box 14)
    Miscellaneous notes, deeds, and other legal papers and documents connected with the Mabis and Eckhart families of Wheeling, West Virginia. 1865-1918.
    The Presbury Family of Maryland and the Ohio Valley, 2 vols.
    Genalogical data on the Alsop, Scovill, Terrell and Williams Families.
  - Cameron, Kenneth Walter (Box 15)
    Othello, a re-examination of the quarto of 1622. A comparative textual study. A thesis…for degree of Master of Arts, West Virginia, June 1931. Typescript.
  - Williams, John
    - Material collected for The Life of John Williams
      - Volumes 1-2 (Box 18)
      - Volumes 3-4 (Box 19)
      - Volume 5 (Box 20)
    - "Thoughts on the Book of Acts" (Box 21)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 22–23)
  - Anglican [contains clippings on the Episcopal Church]
    - Volumes 1-2 (Box 24)
    - Volumes 3-4 (Box 25)
  - Godbey, Allen Howard/Presbury Family (Box 26)
  - Reading [excerpts from readings]
    - Volumes 1-2 (Box 27)
    - Volumes 3-4 (Box 28)
    - Volumes 5-6 (Box 29)
    - Volumes 7-8 (Box 30)
    - Volumes 9-10 (Box 31)
    - Volumes 11-12 (Box 32)
    - Volumes 13-14 (Box 33)
    - Volumes 15-16 (Box 34)
    - Volumes 17-18 (Box 35)
    - Volumes 19-20 (Box 36)
    - Volumes 21-22 (Box 37)
    - Volumes 23-24 (Box 38)
  - Seminary [notebooks of Kenneth Cameron]
    - Volumes 1-2 (Box 39)
    - Volumes 3-4 (Box 40)
    - Volumes 5-6 (Box 41)
    - Volumes 7-8 (Box 42)
  - Printing [contains specimens of printing and calligraphy]
    - Volumes 1-2 (Box 43)
    - Volumes 3-4 (Box 44)
  - Roman [contains clippings on Roman Catholicism] (Box 45)
  - Massachusetts Lyceum [research materials] (Box 46)
  - Oversize
    - West Virginia. Governor, (1909-1913)/Glassock, William Ellsworth, (1862-1913) (Box 47)
    - Commission as Notary Public granted to William Schwertfeger, 1909 December 14 (Box 47)
    - Great Britain [Office of the Revels] (Box 47)
    - Photostats of Declared Accounts [Audit Office], 1609 November 1-1610 October 13 (Box 47)
    - Public Records Office [Bundle 2046, Roll 15] (Box 47)
    - Great Britain. Public Records Office [possibly relating to Mandeville from the calendar of patent rolls], 1330-1349 (Box 47)
    - Genealogical charts (8) which accompany manuscript of the Presbury Family of Maryland and the Ohio Valley (Box 47)
- Cameron letters [sealed letterboxes containing letters from bishops, dignitaries, and others addressed to Kenneth Cameron], Series II (Box 1–36)
  Conditions Governing Access
  The material is unprocessed and may contain sensitive information or be in a physical state that would prohibit use. Researchers wishing to request access should email mssa.assist@yale.edu requesting specific box numbers in order to initiate the review process, which may take several weeks.
- Cameron miscellany, Series III (Box A–K)
  Consists of historical material collected by Kenneth Cameron.